Qi Tang

Address: Saint Louis, MO 63130 || Cell: (314)203-5663 || qi.t@wustl.edu LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/allen-tang-798641224

SUMMARY

Master of Finance (STEM), aiming at finding data-related positions, with sufficient project experience and working experience in **machine learning** (recommendation system/series forecast), **big data analyzing** (Databricks/Azure), **business intelligence** (Tableau/Power BI), and solid programming skills in **Python and SQL**.

EDUCATION

Washington University in St. Louis MO, USA

Aug 2021 - Dec 2022

Master of Finance in Wealth and Asset Management(STEM)

GPA: 3.7/4.0

Coursework: Python and Data Science, A/B testing, SQL, Text mining Nanjing University of Finance & Economics Nanjing, China

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Bachelor of Economics in Finance

GPA: 3.7/4.0

Coursework: Microsoft Office, Statistics, Data Analysis Technology Based on Spark

SKILLS

Machine Learning Techniques:

- Supervised Algorithms: Neural Networks (CNN, RNN), SVM, Naive Bayes, KNN, Text mining (NPL)
- Unsupervised Algorithms: Clustering (K-means, DBSCAN), Principal component analysis (PCA)
- Big Data Techniques: Azure Databricks

Business software: Tableau, Power BI, Microsoft Office

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

San Francisco Crime Analysis in Apache Spark

Oct - Nov 2021

https://github.com/Allen9809/Big-Data-Project-1 SFC-crime-data-analysis

- Built data processing pipeline based on Spark RDD, Spark Dataframe and Spark SQL for big data OLAP.
- Got business insights of the analysis of data, such as the top-3 dangerous districts, percentage of resolution for different category of crime, then post hints toward police policy.
- Explored the spatial distribution of incidents by K-means clustering algorithm, plotted and found the k value with the best silhouette performance, which is 3, then trained the optimal model.

Movie Recommendation System based on Spark ALS

Dec 2021 - Jan 2022

https://github.com/Allen9809/Machine-Learning-Project Movie-Recommendation-System-based-on-ALS

- Performed data ETL on origin movie data from GroupLens and find all movie genres by Spark SQL and OLAP.
- Fitted the ALS model on the training data(80%), then select the hyper-parameters through grid search and 3-fold cross validation to tune the model, and the RMSE on the testing data is 0.88.
- Used the model to make k movie recommendations to users with given userId by Spark SQL.
- Found top k similar movies for a given movieId by KNN algorithm, and distance evaluation are based on both the Euclidean distance and Cosine distance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nestle, Purina

Data science internship.

Saint Louis, USA

May – Aug 2020

- Built a rice consumption amount forecast model for the Purina supply chain department, with an accuracy of 95%, which is acceptable to apply to the business and even 10% higher than the previous model, and it can be generalized to almost all commodities besides rice.
- Developed an ingredient allocation optimization tool for the Purina supply chain department, which can help them rate different series of products based on their current business focus (e.g. profit, supply), thus guiding factories prioritize the production of all products.

Nestle, Purina

Saint Louis, USA Oct 2020 - now

Associate data scientist.

• Assist to develop a truck load optimization engine, which allows the procurement specialists to consolidate the order into full trucks. The average truck utilization is around 98%. It is currently being tested in the warehouse.